Whales already sold. I think what is
what's selling right now, the majority
of it is liquidations.
We are in the middle of Bitcoin fall.
We have no change in the the progress to
million dollar Bitcoin. We just had
Michael say that one. He claims that his
buying strategy buying of Bitcoin does
not move the price. So that puts a floor
on how low it's going to go. Most whales
are hodlers, but you know, there's a lot
of whales, right? If you look at the
past bull cycles, each subsequent
[music] bull cycle had a lower growth
rate than the previous one from trough
to peak. If we assume that this trend
continues, does it not make sense that
mathematically speaking the growth from
trough to peak should approach zero at
some point? That's correct. That's why
the supercycle part is important. A
supercycle has to be 5 [music] years or
more and it has to have an essential
change in the thesis of an asset that
causes the price largely to go up. Twice
every 4-year cycle. They go and sell
near the top, buy back after the bottom
is already a few [music] things have
been consistent across every bottom.
Coin days burned
destroyed, that says it's going to be
around 42,000 at the bottom. Oh. Let's
go back to market for a minute. The um
Wow, you're so much fun, David.
>> [laughter]
[music]
>> We're back at Consensus Miami. Pleased
to welcome back to the show Michael
Terpin for the second time in a year.
Michael Terpin is the author of Bitcoin
supercycle coined by CNBC as the
Godfather of crypto and the founder and
CEO of Transform Ventures. Very pleased
to welcome back to the show Michael and
get his views on where Bitcoin is headed
next on David Lin. Bonnie Cheung.
Michael, tell us where Bitcoin is headed
next, but I'll let you
kick it off with Bonnie first. She's got
some questions for you. Sure. The most
timely one is Saylor's pivot. What is
your thought? I know you are a big
investor in
STRC. You talked about that product that
uh, we last talked, it was 3 months ago.
Tell us what you think. Sure. Um, I
think the pivot, if you want to call it,
he says it's an inoculation. Um, is
because of where he's receiving his
funding now. So, originally, and I've
I've discussed this with Michael at
length, uh, you know, I've I've been to
private events at his home, and uh, you
know, he I've always been an advocate,
if you're if you want to get more
Bitcoin at the end of the day, you
should solve the top and buy back at the
bottom, which is where my uh, my book
has that thesis. Uh, my fund has that
thesis.
And, [snorts] um, you know, he had told
me at the time, and this is probably 2
years ago, that uh, you know, that if he
changes thesis, and did anything other
than always buy, he can certainly buy
more at the bottom, and he has done
that. But, he did anything other than
buy, that certain, you know, Wall Street
buyers would think he changes thesis,
and they wouldn't be as willing to just
perpetually write checks to him. Now,
that was when they were writing checks
to um, the preferred shares, the
different instruments he had before
SCRC. SCRC now has become really a
retail phenomenon, as well as
institutional. And, I think there the
main
um, concern is, you know, how does he
pay the dividends? 11 and 1/2%. I mean,
it's almost three times what T-bills
are, and it's still pretty safe. And, I
think he's just having to show that if
needed, he can sell Bitcoin to to pay
the dividends, cuz there's a lot of it.
And, uh, that doesn't mean, I mean, most
debts, when they sold Bitcoin, it was
because they had to at the bottom of the
market, you know, their their boards in
turmoil and crisis. What a stupid idea,
buying Bitcoin. That's not the the case
with uh, Saylor or MicroStrategy.
They're all firm long-term believers,
and his thesis of borrowing 11 and 1/2,
and having appreciation of uh, more than
20% per year, um, you know, still works
uh, with the right financial
engineering. And, so, you have to have
that little inoculation, as he says, or
escape valve, that if all of a sudden
you need to go and sell,
um you can. I just really don't see him
doing it anytime soon.
Interesting. You're on the show a year
ago,
Vegas, BTC Vegas, you outlined the path
for Bitcoin to reach a million dollars
by 2033. Do you still hold that the
cycle will continue as you talked about
last year? I do. I have no change in the
the um um progress to a million dollar
Bitcoin. Okay, but short-term you told
me offline you're a little bit skeptical
of the price action going forward
upward. Well, it's it's really not a
change at all my thesis either. We are
in the middle of Bitcoin fall. Uh I'd
say the one thing that has changed from
a year ago is STRC.
Um STRC has a lot of uh capital deriving
bigger purchases of Bitcoin by
MicroStrategy than you normally would
have had in a in a bear market. I mean,
he's you know, raised I think 7 billion
uh you know, in one day.
X dividend day of this last time. Um you
know, I saw him at the the Bitcoin
conference just this last week in Las
Vegas, and he did a special session for
the whales after his main uh speech. And
uh you know, he had said pretty much his
thesis is to get to 10 billion dollars a
month and then to 100 billion and then
to a trillion and then to one 10
trillion. And that as that goes up, he
can buy more and more Bitcoin. I don't
know if he's ever going to get to 10
trillion, but uh he's certainly going to
get to 10 billion pretty quickly, and
one could foresee someday him getting to
100 billion a month. And um that's a lot
of buy pressure. So, I think what that
has done as um
perhaps uh put a a floor on how low it
can go.
Um in February, I thought that since we
didn't, you know, hit the 200-week
moving average that has always marked
the bottom in the past, um
we we came a little short of it. It
would have to go below 57K. We went to
60, and then we bounced hard off of it.
And you know, the capitulation phase,
three times out of three,
it doesn't bounce. It just lays there,
and people are like running away from
Bitcoin for a while.
>> floor. We just had Michael Saylor on
earlier today, and he claims, correct me
if I'm wrong, Bonnie, but that he claims
that his buying strategy, buying of
Bitcoin, does not move the price. He's
very humble about it.
>> you What do you have to say about that?
>> say it moved the price the day he buys
it, but what I think it does is it puts
a floor on how low it's going to go
because I would think that he would buy
a lot more if it actually went down to
say 39 or something like that. And I
think that every time he buys it,
it doesn't immediately raise the price.
It's actually been surprising how little
it does raise the price cuz he's buying
it over time. He doesn't declare it
until, you know, his Monday when he says
how much he bought, and it's OTC, right?
I mean, OTC masks a lot of um buying and
selling behavior. I mean, historically,
a lot of the volatility in the era that
whales controlled things,
um were that they would, you know, buy
things OTC, and then they would dump on
the market and cause things down and
then short at the same time.
That's behavior that uh Wall Street
knows how to do, and they've done it in
other assets, and I think you could see
around the 1010 scenario that there was
a bit of that gamesmanship going on.
How does the volatility of Bitcoin
change over time as more whales
accumulate a larger share of the
outstanding Bitcoin in the market?
Well, I don't think the percentage of
whales is going up. I think the
percentage of institutions is going up.
Um I do believe, though, that the whales
who sold in October, the vast majority
of them, are going to buy back the same
amount or more because that's the whole
thesis of my, you know, four seasons of
bit of Bitcoin, um is that, you know,
you have four seasons driven on fear and
greed, and that if you sell at the end
of Bitcoin summer, you know, the price
is a lot higher than it is at the at the
start of Bitcoin winter. So, Bitcoin
follows where all your decision-making
that makes a difference happens. If
you're accurately able to tell the first
day of Bitcoin fall, which is the bubble
popping, and the last day of Bitcoin
fall, which is the final capitulation,
you make a lot of money. It would be
more than more than 4x per cycle the
last time. If more institutions
accumulate Bitcoin, in other words,
let's say Michael Saylor's strategy and
other treasury companies like it, if
they accumulate a larger percentage of
Bitcoin outstanding, doesn't that make
the market overall more illiquid and
therefore more volatile? Does that make
sense?
If they accumulate them as permanent
capital? Yeah. Cuz ETFs are certainly
not permanent capital. They They do move
it out. They move in and out um less
than um
than say first-generation retail does. I
mean, first-generation retail, um which
I'd say is the the majority of retail
buyers of ETFs, are not people who are
already on Coinbase. They're ones who
are uncomfortable, you know, doing
self-custody, buying even on Coinbase,
and all of a sudden it's like, "Oh, I
can do it through my Charles Schwab
account." And so, they bought, and they
typically are a little bit less paper
hand in terms of uh selling when the
price goes down. They do sell net, but
it's been a lower level than um say 4
years ago, 8 years ago, when you know,
it was just people who had heard about
Bitcoin, bought because their friends
were making money, bought at the top,
and then panic sold uh at or near the
bottom. They're still doing that, but in
less numbers. Maybe because they call
the broker and they say, "No, no, no,
no, no. Keep this in your IRA for 10
years." And so, you you do have um less
selling at the bottom, but you do have
selling.
>> A
seller is buying at a crazy big amount
and you said it's OTC. So, someone is
selling.
Are we talking about the whales? Whales
already sold. I think what is what's
selling right now, the majority of it is
liquidations.
You have an unprecedented number of, you
know, new ways of
of getting liquidated.
You know, we didn't have,
you know, very many perps in the in the
crypto space 4 years ago. And now you
got hyper liquid, you've got all these
other vehicles where you can go and you
got exchanges where you could do, I
guess he had some 4 years ago, but
BitMEX was first one to do like you
know, 100x leverage. But you have more
people using those and using trading
bots etc. among retail and you know, a
lot of them think, you know, they make
some money, they think they're too smart
for the room and they they go in, you
know, irresponsibly long or short and
get liquidated. And so I say
liquidations, you can see the size of
the numbers. That's that's where that's
where a lot of the selling is, I
wouldn't say most of it, but But you
just said whales have already sold.
Whales who are not playing trading
games. Yeah, whales who say sold a
significant position sold, you know,
much pretty much in September, October,
November. And you think these whales are
trading? They're not hot wallets.
Um most whales are hot wallets. Okay.
But, you know, there's a lot of whales,
right? I mean, if you look at the number
that sold, it was still, I don't know,
maybe 10% or less of the overall um
wallets that have uh you know, been
holding it the asset for more than say,
you know, 8 years or so.
Um certainly 10 years.
Uh a lot of them are ones that just
never moved or they moved once to, you
know, put it into a segment wallet. And
the opsec. And so, the ones who are
trading, there are a number that trade.
You can see it on chain
twice every 4-year cycle. They go and
sell near the top. They usually get a
little bit, you know, wrong.
Um you know, they usually sell a little
bit early.
Um and then they buy back um
after the bottom's already in. They
usually come back a little bit late cuz
they think it's going to go lower. And
you saw that very very clearly in the
'21 '22. Whales selling at the top and
uh buying back at the bottom.
Last time we talked, it was at around,
if I remember correctly, about 60K. And
you said we were going lower.
That's correct. That was uh that was
when it was just you and me in Hong
Kong. And uh yeah, it was at 60K. It
came close to the bottom, but because we
have yet a few things have been
consistent across every bottom. And for
February to have been the bottom like
Michael Saylor says, it probably is.
Would it mean that the majority of
things have changed. And usually every
cycle one or two things change, but when
the majority change, then you have to
really wonder about the cycle overall.
And I don't think the majority of things
have changed.
Because every cycle so far the bottom
has taken roughly a year. Uh 4 years ago
it was 1 year to the day. 4 years before
that was 3 days off of the year. And the
first having it was one year plus a
couple weeks.
For it to all of a sudden be over in
like 12 weeks, doesn't seem to make a
lot of sense. That's time-based
capitulation usually is necessary for
some of the weak hands, but not perhaps
paper hands to finally give up and say,
"You know, this is not for me." Um or
for them to bet in the wrong direction
cuz they're not experienced traders and
get liquidated. Um I mean, usually a lot
of traders the first time that they try
derivatives get wiped out.
And so, um
the other one is is a number of
statistics that you know, just technical
statistics that all point toward an
October low. One of them is
uh
days
coin days burned or destroyed.
Um that says it's going to be around
42,000 at the bottom. Um that's been
right every other time. Um and then
another one is months after the initial
high kicked off the bull market. So,
just like we've had three times in a row
now
that from bottom to top it was 35
months. It was within days, right, of
the bottom and then the bubble popping.
Um
similarly, there've been twice in a row
where from the initial all-time high
to um
the capitulation was 23 months.
23 months would also put us in October.
The only like
you know, kind of like question mark
here
is whether you count the initial
all-time high before the having
when the ETFs,
um you know, popped us over the '21 high
in '24
um because of all this pent-up demand.
We went to 73,850 and then we went down
uh at the having and I talked about this
in my book. I thought that you can't
have a new all-time high for this cycle
a month before the having cuz that's
last cycle. And typically every Bitcoin
summer is when you have your first new
high all-time high and then things just
take off like a rocket ship. In this
case it went down to the having. And
where it took off like a rocket ship was
when you then hit 73 850 again in
November. So here's the interesting
thing.
If because we've never tested this
before because this is the first time
we've ever had a new all-time high
before having, if the 23 months is
starting at that ETF month, then 23
months was February.
And that matches to where we ended up
having the first 60K low. So I mean,
I've been saying consistently that I
thought it was about, you know, 70%
chance that the bottom was not in yet. I
mean, today we actually had the first
day we tipped up to 83. Um, I think it's
a good opportunity to short.
Um, my fund is doing that.
Um, but you know, we were we're
certainly
I'd say right now it's probably more
than a more like a 40% chance that the
bottom was in and
you know, we're we're headed up slowly.
And so if that's the case, we've got
some hedging to go the other direction.
We think
we're pretty confident about two to one
odds that we are going lower. And that
anything I sell in the 80s I can buy
back in the 60s to perhaps the 50s. I
don't think right now the only thing
that's changed since February is I don't
think we're going to probably go below
40. I think that the buying of STRC is
really provide and the ETFs has really
been providing a little bit of a of a
cushion to mean that we don't drop quite
as low. And every every having cycle
you've had diminishing returns. You've
also had diminishing losses. And this
was certainly the lowest of the
diminishing returns. It was barely 2X. I
thought it'd be 3X with the neutral
macro. And then I was expecting that
we'd be down about
maybe 66% and so far we've only been
down like 54 I think or something for
for the 60k from 126. So, I I think
we'll still get down a bit below 60, but
it wouldn't surprise me if it, you know,
goes down like somewhere between say
48 and 55, maybe even 57. As long as it
goes below that sort of like 60k mark in
February and touches the 200-week moving
average, then I feel like the cycle's
still intact.
AI has been
disrupting the entire software industry.
The IGV ETF, which is a software index
ETF, is down about 25% year to date.
Mainstream media is writing that a
anything built on code is being
repriced. So, can you expect Bitcoin,
which is also built on code, to see a
similar repricing at some point?
No.
Bitcoin has withstood an awful lot of
attacks. I don't think there's going to
be some version of mythos that's going
to unwind the code in Bitcoin. It just
has too much protection behind it. It's
not just code. It's code and also all
these blocks that have been permanently
sealed. So, I mean, quantum, of course,
its threat is that it can go in and, you
know, figure out,
you know, what a private key is by just
trying, you know, what would normally
take billions of years and that in the
future could take a few minutes to go
and guess every single variation of like
a 45 character
alphanumeric string.
But, I think before that happens, which
I believe are still 15-20 years away,
A, they're going to go after
other SHA-256 targets like the defense
industry, hospitals, banks. I mean,
these are all built on SHA-256. So, if
you can crack Satoshi's wallet or you
can crack JP Morgan, you know, you're
probably going to have to go after JP
Morgan first. But, you know, again, with
Bitcoin, you have to go out after wallet
at a time. You're not going to crack
every wallet in Bitcoin.
So, it's a very distributed
decentralized system. So, I don't
believe I think that it's very possible
that, um, you'll have AI,
um, crack some significant, um,
uh, smart contract and that will be a
crisis that will, uh, drive the price of
Ethereum way down and there'll probably
be collateral damage on Bitcoin. I I
would see that as one of the main things
that could happen, uh, between now and
October that would then be your FTX
moment. You know, let's say Lido
cracked, right? How much is staked on
Lido?
And, uh, and and we got sucked out and
goes to North Korea. Um, that would
definitely cause a lot of collateral
damage and I could see that bring us
down, you know, into the 40s, perhaps.
But, without that, without something
significant, if it's just the garden
variety, you know, hedge fund unwinding,
um, you know, we're probably going to,
you know, probably only go down a little
bit below 60, 50s. That's a very
interesting topic because everyone is
talking about how quantum versus
Bitcoin, but nobody's talking about
Ethereum. Let's focus on that because a
lot of Ethereum holders out there
they have the same question.
So, do you think quantum computers can
crack Ethereum first? I I wasn't talking
about quantum and Ethereum. I was
talking about smart contracts built on
Ethereum. And Right. Okay.
Yeah, there's a difference. There Yeah,
right. There wouldn't so much be, uh,
quantum, it would be, um, some of these
newer, um, frontier models, um, in AI
like Mythos that they're afraid to
release that they get so powerful. And
now, apparently, all the other ones have
ones that are Mythos strength. So, if
that gets out and it gets into the wrong
hands, um, it could go and find exploits
to go and look, some of the biggest
things that almost cracked Ethereum in
the past, you go back to, um,
uh, the DAO and you had the hacker of
the DAO back in 2016. I mean, literally
Vitalik made the decision along with,
you know, um the community to roll back
the Ethereum blockchain and get rid of
that one hack that was at that point it
was $60 million that was a double-digit
uh amount of the entire value of
Ethereum. And uh it collapsed the price
of Ethereum from like $30 down to about
$6, but obviously it recovered.
>> [snorts]
>> Can you explain from a supercycle
perspective why Bitcoin, stocks, talking
about the Nasdaq, and gold have been
moving in tandem for the last 3 months?
If you look at this chart, for example,
I I overlaid it with the 10-year yield,
just ignore that at the end, that's the
orange line, but if you look at the
other three lines, this is the last 6
months. They seem to have been moving
together for the most part.
Well, the last since the war though, um
Bitcoin was flat and then it moved up
quite a bit and gold really hasn't done
the same.
So, I mean, I haven't done a day-by-day
comparison with gold, but uh it seemed
like Bitcoin was outperforming gold for
the first time in a while um after the
war. Yes, that's correct. Would that
change the narrative of gold being an
anti-war
hedge and Bitcoin taking on that role?
Not yet. Okay. I mean, I think for the
most part that look, Bitcoin is digital
gold has been the narrative for many
years and it's still obviously a small
percentage of what the gold market is,
but it has certain um
attributes that for many make it uh
you know, more um robust than gold. You
know, the fact that it's, you know, it's
um scarcity
uh keeps on going um
down in terms of supply and demand every
4 years where it 0.88 it's going to go
to 0.44, 0.22 and gold, you know, keeps
keeps They keep finding new gold every
year, right? And it keeps around 1 and
1/2% and we don't know if in another 100
years it's still going to be 1 and 1/2
percent, but if it is that means 150%
more gold
in 100 years and only, you know, 4% more
Bitcoin and then none.
Would [snorts] you say that
liquidity is still the dominant driver
of Bitcoin? I think it was Lyn Alden who
brought this to our attention a few
years ago when she overlaid global M2
money supply growth with the price of
Bitcoin and there was a very strong
correlation there.
The thesis being that global liquidity
drives capital into risk assets such as
Bitcoin.
Would that disrupt your cycle's thesis?
No, I think for the most part they're
complementary. Okay. Um, the global
liquidity tends to
be driven by presidential elections
>> Okay.
>> and policies and I think that it was not
an accident, I say this in my book, it
was not an accident that Satoshi planned
to have the halvings around presidential
elections and
and then you end up having the bear
market during midterms.
>> Sorry, how is that not an accident? I
said I don't believe it's an accident.
He never He never put it in He never
said specifically in the white paper
that he was going to have this, but I
believe that it's not an accident that,
you know, the halvings have been 2012,
2016, 2020, 2024, the next one's going
to be 2028.
>> [snorts]
>> I don't believe that he planned to
have it move out of the presidential
years so quickly because 2016, I mean,
if you take away 2016, we've been pretty
close to the four-year cycle. There's
never been four-year cycle, right? It's
a 210,000 block cycle. And the algorithm
is supposed to go and make 10-minute
blocks and if they're exactly 10
minutes, you get about four years. And
they've been
if they're if they're if they're less
than that, you make
you adjust the difficulty to make them
longer. If they're longer than that, you
adjust the difficulty to make them make
them shorter. So in other words, you add
difficulty or subtract it to make it
easier or harder for mining because
otherwise, You, you you have a four-year
cycle and you might have a two-year
cycle, they might have an eight-year
cycle. And so, that's the whole thing
about it also creates extra security for
the network. That's I have a whole
chapter in my book about mining and and
the economics of that. That is very
interesting because then the four-year
cycle is based on US election. So,
Satoshi planned this around US. I
believe so, cuz US is still the most
powerful economy in the world. It
affects all the global
>> So, it doesn't matter where this person
is from.
He realized or she realized this.
Yes, I think that you could say that
Satoshi, whether it's one person or a
team, uh had an, you know, intricate
understanding of uh of economics. And
predicting that it won't change for the
next hundreds of years. Yeah, and I I
I think that once you get past the first
five, six, seven cycles, um and you get
into the super cycle effect that I'm
I've discussed in the book, cuz right
now, even though we're only in the fifth
cycle, we are 96% out of Bitcoin.
And so, I mean, the most money to be
made was in the first cycle when you
were able to go in,
um you know, when
you could have mined things that
effectively below a penny, and you
couldn't have sold them at all until
2010, but uh if you were a believer in
the thesis, Mihal Finney, who received
the first Bitcoin, was the first
Bitcoiner other than the Satoshi that'd
be mining, said, "This is interesting,
uh you know,
everything he said words, but it was
something like, "This is an interesting
situation. This is either going to zero
or to $10 million a coin."
Do you think he's Satoshi?
He's certainly one of the ones who's
suspected of being Satoshi.
Um you know, it's it's still a mystery.
There's about 20 people that you you
have valid reasons to think is Satoshi,
and no one has proven it. Um I think at
some point there'll be reasonable proof.
Um I mean, the latest one, of course,
uh you know, has been, you know,
um Adam Back and uh, but he denies it
and uh, a lot of people poo-poo that one
and you know, I think there it's mainly
because of the way he spells things and
the fact that he's uh, you know, kind of
British influence in his background and
you know, there's a few people say, "Oh,
this thing was
you know,
in Canada when it was posted or
whatever." So, I think right now it's
still guessing.
Just going back to the market for a
minute. The um,
Wow, you're so much fun, David.
>> [laughter]
>> We can go back to that if you like. Is
that CIA got the creator of
Bitcoin? Um, I I I I I want to know how
much of Bitcoin's rise over the last 10
years has been due to
fiat debasement and sovereign debt
accumulation. You buy into that theory?
>> of it. A lot of it. I mean, you know,
you talk about liquidity, there's no
greater um, you know, creator of
liquidity than money printing. Yeah. And
when the US prints money, the rest of
the world seems to print more. And that
would erode trust in the fiat system and
It erodes trust just like, look, the I I
I speak in my book about um, the
commodity super cycles and you know,
we've had really three of them in the
last 100 years and a super cycle overall
and this goes back to, you know, Elliot
and the Elliot Wave and what he said,
you know, 100 years ago almost. And um,
you know,
that a super cycle he he has the grand
super cycle, a little mini super cycles.
A super cycle is has to be 5 years or
more and um, it has to have a essential
change in the thesis of an asset um,
that causes the price largely to go up.
Um, and in the first super cycle in the
last century for commodities was gold in
the '70s because you had a fundamental
change, two of them really. You had
Nixon taking us off the uh, the gold
standard and then in the same decade you
had the re-legalization of Americans'
abilities to own gold. So, all of a
sudden you had a new reason to buy gold
and you had more people who were able to
buy.
And so, that led to a quadrupling of the
uh, price of gold as you well know in
the in the 1970s. The second um super
cycle was more broad-based across
most commodities that were used in
building,
um copper, nickel, etc. In the '90s
because China had
hyperindustrialization.
And um in my book I I I discuss that CME
had said, I think in '23,
that we may be starting
uh a new super cycle based on money
printing and monetary debasement, but
we're not sure yet. Well, obviously what
happened in 2025 is we're sure now.
Have you heard of Neil Howe's Fourth
Turning? Yes.
So, for the audience just to recap, the
Fourth Turning argues that every 80
years society reaches some sort of
institutional breakdown. I wonder if
Bitcoin has been rising in the last
couple of years as a reflection of the
coming of the Fourth Turning and is
really just an erosion of societal
trust.
You know, it's an interesting question.
Maybe long before the Fourth Turning
came out, there were a lot of theses
about the
uh you know, you have to wait sort of
like two generations before people
forget everything and things repeat. Um
and 80 years, you know, has been the lot
of times people
uh you know, disagree about when the 80
years was. Was it, you know, 1929? Was
it 1945? You know, when when did sort of
the last uh 80-year cycle end?
Obviously, there have been there have
been dramatic things that have happened
every decade for the most part. And um
from technology, it's been
very consistent for the last
five decades or so that there's been at
least one major new disruptive
technology every decade and they tend to
start taking off in the early part of
the decades and then like, you know,
sort of like the bubble pops at the end.
Um if you look at uh you know, just in
the last few decades,
uh the uh the internet, you know, kind
of the web started in '91 even though
the internet been around as a, you know,
DARPA experiment since the '60s, but the
the World Wide Web started in '91. When
I got in in like early '93, it was still
barely there. I had to, you know, get my
web browser from Marc Andreessen's dorm
room, effectively. It was, you know, it
was a university project. And by the end
of the '90s, you had the dot-com bubble
and trillions of dollars made and lost.
And so now you go 10 years later to the
2000s, and you had a similar phenomenon
with Web 2, right?
Social media was just was nothing at the
start of the decade. It was little
experiments with this little company
called LinkedIn. Then MySpace. And by,
you know, the end of the decade, you
know, you had the the big unicorns and
you know, and then that bubble, you
know, kind of popped. Not really, cuz
obviously it it kind of went down and
now there's some of the largest
entities in the world. But the start of
2010s, you know, Bitcoin was still very
nascent phase. I mean, you could have
bought, you know, for pennies in 2010.
And then by the end of the decade, it
was almost 20,000, sorry,
60,000 dollars by by 2020. And so I'd
say that this decade has been AI, right?
2022 is when uh um
when the, you know, OpenAI came out with
its first commercial
uh LLM, and that broke all records for
how quickly a product could be adapted.
Netflix had the record for getting to a
million users. It took about a year.
OpenAI took five days.
And now it's closer to a billion.
And so it's just been, I mean, AI is
like the internet has been, you know,
percolating along for a long time.
I've I've followed AI for many decades.
My
my younger brother graduated from MIT's
artificial intelligence lab, and I
thought in the '90s that it was going to
take off with the expert systems and
Prolog, and it never did. And obviously
LLMs is what was needed, and now agents
to really,
you know, it's now
a vast majority of the increase in value
in the S&P.
How does that tie back to Bitcoin? If AI
is the new sexy investment, then
what is Bitcoin? Sure. So, it's two
things. I mean, first of all, it's a
giant pie, right? And um yes, there
there's a lot of stock market investors
now shifting from other parts of the
stock market to the Mag 7, to
AI. There's a big part of uh
institutional, you know, Sand Hill, you
know, Road VCs putting 80-something
percent of their of their of their
budgets into uh into AI. But, these are
within the fine the asset classes,
right? And so, it's not like gold
investors are dumping gold and putting
everything into AI. And the same thing
with crypto. Same thing with Bitcoin.
You probably have on the fringe some
you know, disgruntled or just sort of
people who've always been diversified
going, "Say, hey, maybe this year I'm
only going to put, you know, 20% into
Bitcoin. I'm going to put the 10% into
AI stocks or into AI startups." But, um
you know, the nice thing is that the
monetary supply keeps growing, so
there's
there's room for you to grow as long as
you keep on the money printing.
I think the other aspect of AI though
that's interesting is yes, it probably,
along with prediction markets, takes
away from some of the dollars that might
have otherwise gone into Bitcoin um and
other crypto projects. Uh but, at the
same time,
there has been,
you know, a lot of growth even in the
bear market in the AI uh tokens, which
are still very nascent. I mean, they had
a they had a big run-up at the end of uh
4, I believe it was.
Um where they went from, you know, they
some of them went 100x
um from October to December. And then
the and then the bubble popped on that
one. And um now they're starting to run
up again cuz they went up, they went
down. Since the last 90 days, the Venice
token, VVD, is up uh
500%. Went from like $2 to almost $10.
Um you also have uh
you know, other ones like BitTensor has
doubled. Um and that's still nowhere
near its high from the last time. I
believe that, uh, you know, the AI
tokens are going to be are going to
outperform Bitcoin in the next 3 years,
um, the top ones at least, and that a
lot of those gains will then roll back,
um, into Bitcoin and increase. If you
have new money coming into the AI tokens
that's from outside of the system, and
then eventually when someone sells, they
put it into Bitcoin.
Um,
and then stable coins are again a
massive,
um, new force in the economics of of
crypto. The more that you have people
having stable coins, they're now very
easily able to buy Bitcoin, Ethereum,
any other token cuz they they now
finally have a wallet. And you've had
this mass explosion. I don't think when,
I mean, as you know, I was involved in
the dawn of Tether when the, Brock
Pierce and and and Reeve Collins and,
you know, the team there, uh, Craig put
together Tether in Santa Monica in early
2014. And then they ended up selling it
to Bitfinex and spun off as Tether.
I mean, their thoughts in those days was
we're going to be able to go in, uh, be
able to have a coin that represents a
dollar so that you can
be able to trade between exchanges and
not wait 3 days, and we'll make money on
interest from banks. That was it. I
don't think any of them thought that one
day would be a, you know,
making 20 billion dollars a year in the,
in the T-bills, right? With 100
employees. Michael, I'm curious how the
future of Bitcoin cycles will progress.
If you look at the past bull cycles,
each subsequent bull cycle had a lower
growth rate than the previous one from
trough to peak. If we assume that this
trend continues, does it not make sense
that mathematically speaking, the the
the growth from trough to peak should
approach zero at some point? That is
correct. That's why the super cycle part
is important. So, we have had
logarithmically diminishing returns,
um, and we've had arithmetically
diminishing losses. So,
your your first cycle, which is before
the halving, and
may or may not be as relevant because
you didn't have a halving yet, but um
from the lowest quoted price, the first
sale of Bitcoin for 1/10 of a penny, to
the high was
3,000x, 1/10 of a penny to $30. And then
it crashed down to a dollar, 97% drop.
The second cycle after the first
halving, you went up 100x from $12 to
$1,200, and then you crashed 85%. The
third cycle, you ended up going up 30x,
and then you crashed 83%. The fourth
cycle, you ended up So,
3,130,
next number's 10, right? In that sort of
uh progression. And so, I was projecting
that we would have had a 10x increase um
from the $8,700
um halving in 2000 during COVID times,
and um you know, we ended up getting cut
short around 68, 69k.
And I think that's because of macro. The
bad macro is Biden's war on crypto, uh
you know, the choke point 2.0, and the
rapid rise of interest rates.
That I'm surprised it only got clipped
by, you know, 20%. Um but it did. And
so, and you ended up having it go up So,
it went up 8x instead of 10x, and you
ended up having this suppressed demand
um show up at the end of the
cycle,
uh the fourth cycle,
um the month before the ha- the the
halving um with the ETFs uh going live
and uh setting 73,000, which was roughly
9x.
And um and then, you know, we ended up
having a 75% drop to the FTX lows of
15k. So, I projected based on that that
we were going to go up 3x plus or minus
macro.
Everybody and their brother thought that
with Trump being elected it'd be
tailwinds, positive macro.
Unfortunately, they didn't realize that
uh you know, President Trump has you
know, been great for crypto but has been
a chaotic with his community
communications and
every time he tweets something
you think by now people realize that he
blocks a lot that he just plays you
know, read the art of the deal you know,
he'll ask for one thing and and like
overstate you know, what bad things are
going to happen to get the midpoint and
make it seem like a win. This is very
common in politics but the media and the
markets just get freaked out whenever
you know, and and you end up having that
leading to 1010.
Even though um the high in in
October happened exactly where it had
the last couple of cycles. There was
another
you know,
sort of version of reading the data that
would that said it could have gone
another month or two. Um
you know, if there was enough buying
demand and if there wasn't the black
swan and you know, 1010 ended being that
black swan where you know, you had this
perfect storm of Trump tweeting buying
and selling like and then
cutting off its market makers ability to
short. They
deleveraged them. And so that led to
like just the free fall in price.
And you know, there was some tradfi uh
coincidences that were going on in terms
of like who was shorting what and
you know, what messages they were
sending to their brokers that
you know, appeared that there was number
of people who very quickly acted upon
that
event and
you know,
sold very quickly and and shorted and
really caused that initial drop that you
know, started the bear market.
My last question for you is your comment
on the 10:00 a.m. dump by Jane Street.
>> Yes. Uh that is what people think
happened. I am not sure and I'd love
your opinion on it. Well, it's been
widely reported. I I don't have any
proof of it but it's been widely
reported enough that it sounded like uh
uh
like it probably happened and uh
and it's not happening anymore.
Um the the
>> It stopped after.
>> it stopped, right? And the price have
gone up since then.
Um but the the thesis was that uh Jane
Street was systematically selling at
10:00 a.m. which is a half hour after
the markets open and then like many
short sellers do, flooding the market
with like "Ah, price is going to dump
today because of XYZ news." Well, price
is going to dump because you were
systematically selling at 10:00 a.m. And
then they would have shorts in and they
would make money.
But is it is that legal? Basically, it
is legal.
Well, it's if you're not doing it with a
commodity and with a security,
um I you know, Bitcoin is not as
well-defined in terms of you know, what
you can do in terms of uh shorting etc.
I'm not a lawyer. Yeah. Um and I know a
lot of Wall Street banks pay fines and
they're they're they're fraction of what
they make on the trade. So, um you know,
all I know is that um
there's still a lot of uh games that the
whales played that are being played by
Wall Street now or certainly can be.
That argument is so if we see the
inflows of Bitcoin spot ETF, that is
what retail investors see. That doesn't
equally mean that they're not shorting
with derivatives.
So, that is one of the concerns people
have.
Well, look, you have a lot of invisible
parts of the market in stocks as well.
You have dark pools, you get OTC desks
and the historically, the way that the
whales would sort of um make money in a
bear market would be or in any market
would be they would, you know,
um buy OTC
and then short on chain in a smaller
exchange and the rest would
automatically follow, right? Because you
have very quick arbitrage between the
exchanges and then at the same time they
would have a a large short position in
and they would like, you know, say it's
say the price is 85,000,
they say they're going to go and um
you know, short it that it's going to go
down to 75,000. They have enough um
Bitcoin that they can cause the dump by
themselves and then they buy it back at
at at where they dumped it to and they
also collect money on the short.
Is that why Okay, there are a few people
that are very famous on chain for losing
money,
but
I would assume that they're doing
something else on the exchanges.
You want to tell me about Mr. Winn?
Um you know, there's a number of people
on X who've been, you know, loudly
saying they made a billion, lost a
billion or whatever. So, uh I can't
speak to to the veracity of their uh of
their data. I mean,
uh there's a number of YouTubers that go
on and actually show their trades, but
doesn't mean they're not doing something
other than those trades. So, uh you
know, there's there's a lot The great
thing about the Bitcoin market is that
you uh you can see a lot of what happens
on chain.
Obviously, particularly with the ETFs,
you know, a lot of it is, you know,
behind the the walls of uh CoinDesk,
right? I'm sorry, Coinbase. And uh you
know, and and also in other derivatives
markets that are not showing up on chain
because they're they're trading uh you
know, stocks.
I mean, look, this has been common in
gold for a long time, too. Anything you
would change in your book if you had to
rewrite it today?
Last question for me. I would probably
go into some more details about what
could have happened at the end of uh
uh this cycle cuz I think I probably
oversimplified
um you know, the most likely scenario
being uh um that it was going to go to
about, you know,
about like, you know, the midpoint with
neutral macro, which would be about 193.
I probably should have uh put in a few
more formulas like uh like the 35-month.
And uh I just didn't want to make it too
technical. All right. Well, I'll
encourage everyone to check out Bitcoin
Supercycle and check out Michael's work.
Links down below. Also, check out
Bonnie's channel. Subscribe. And yours.
Thank you.